# DAMIAN C. ROSSNEY

## WEB DEVELOPER

rossney.net

**(**914) 227-4202

in linkedin.com/in/damianrossney

**O** dcr8898

### Skills

#### **OVERVIEW**

Excellent written and oral communication skills

Outstanding research skills

High technical proficiencies

Highly motivated and disciplined

Organized and detail oriented

Resourceful and hard working

Able to work independently or in collaboration

Adept at performing multiple complex tasks simultaneously

### **TECHNICAL**

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript

Frameworks:

Rails, Sinatra, jQuery, Handlebars

Databases:

PostrgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite

Front End:

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Skeleton

Testing:

Rspec, Jasmine, Capybara, SimpleCov

Version Control:

Git, GitHub, BitBucket

Continuous Deployment:

Heroku

Continuous Integration:

CircleCI

Methodologies:

Agile, Kanban, TDD, OOD/OOP, MVC, REST, AJAX

#### OTHER

Experienced instructor (legal research and computer skills)

## **Summary**

I am a full stack developer with prior experience as a paralegal. I enjoy solving complex problems and building practical things. When I realized that the most interesting task I completed as a paralegal was parsing a huge FDA database with raw SQL to extract adverse incident data on a robotic surgery device, I knew it was time for a change. On my new path, I have developed projects using Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, JavaScript (native, jQuery, Handlebars, etc.), SQL (PostgreSQL, MySQL, and SQLite), ORMs (primarily Active Record), HTML5, and CSS3. I have utilized Test-Driven Development using Rspec, Jasmine, and Capybara, and followed Agile methodologies such as Kanban. I am currently expanding my repertoire to include additional web languages, such as PHP and Python.

### **Projects**

### There's A Board (Core Developer) (https://github/theresaboard)

An open source mentorship app initially designed around the simple idea of matching students with student-tutors based on availability and study topic, There's A Board evolved into a powerful support platform allowing students, alumns, and employee mentors to connect for studying, tutoring, and skill development. There's A Board was adopted by Dev Bootcamp and is currently in use as their tool for managing both paid and volunteer mentors. Built on a Rails backend, with a custom JavaScript front end, with full test coverage of the back end. We employed agile methods based on kanban, and utilized both continuous integration and continuous deployment.

- Multiple external APIs, including Auth0, GitHub, SendGrid, Twilio, Particle, and Google Calendar.
- jQuery, FullCalendar, Bootstrap, for front end presentation and calendar interaction.
- Test Driven Development using Rspec.
- CircleCI and SimpleCov for continuous integration and coverage analysis.
- · GitHub for version control.
- Heroku for continuous deployment.

## **Experience**

# Wilson Elser Moskowitz Edelman & Dicker, LLP Senior Paralegal

White Plains, NY Mar 2010 to May 2015

Managed complex litigation from inception through trial, settlement, and appeals, including:

- Legal Research: Dispositive motions, procedural issues, and appeals.
- Investigative Research: Background research on parties and expert witnesses, medical research for both causation and liability.
- Electronic Discovery: Forensic collection and preservation of electronic data, and processing and evaluation of data produced by adversarial parties
- Discovery Tracking: Custom database development to track, organize, and analyze documents by their contents and associated metadata.
- Trial Technology: Assisted in the presentation of evidence, including electronic evidence and expert material; coordinated and developed trial technology, including trial infrastructure (networks, etc.), presentation technology, and evidence preparation.
- Exhibit Creation: Demonstrative exhibits for trials, including both video and illustrations; also collaborated with experts witnesses to coordinate and prepare expert exhibits and presentations.
- Legal presentations: For example, researched and created presentation on the medical record privacy implications of the Health Insurance Portability and Privacy Act, delivered to prospective client hospitals and nursing homes.

# Bartlett McDonough Bastone & Monaghan, LLP

White Plains, NY Jan 2005 to Mar 2010

Supported attorneys through all phases of litigation and appeals in a mid-sized defense-litigation firm. Primarily medical malpractice defense, some premises liability and product liability defense, a small number of labor matters and plaintiff personal injury cases.

# Paralegal & Research Assistant Independent

New York 1999 to 2005

Directly assisted clients appearing before state and federal administrative agencies. Conducted research, drafted correspondence, memoranda, and appellate briefs. Assisted attorneys on a case-by-case basis in all phases of administrative proceedings and civil and criminal litigation.

## **Education**

Litigation Paralegal

Dev Bootcamp Graduate 2015

Skidmore College UWW

B.S. Business Administration (Minor in Math) 1998